A Guide to the Papers of Bonnie S. Ball 1960-1996
Roanoke Public Libraries
Roanoke Public Libraries
A Guide to the Papers of Bonnie S. Ball
Roanoke Public Libraries
2014.1.4
1 record storage box
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donor unknown
Biographical Note
Bonnie Sage was born on December 17, 1901 near Stickleysville, Virginia. She was the fourth of thirteen children. Bonnie later became a teacher and taught all over Virginia and adjoining states. During her teaching career, she met and married Palmer Ball. After 33 years of teaching, Bonnie retired to Big Stone Gap, Virginia. She was a member of several historical societies, the DAR, UDC, was a correspondent for several papers and publications, she published several books, and participated in church activities. Mrs. Ball passed away on May 11, 1996 at the age of 95. She was a well-known and respected genealogist.
Scope and Content
The Bonnie S. Ball collection comprises 1 record storage box. The collection is made up of handwritten notes by Ball, all done on standard notebook paper; genealogical charts; an 8x12 scrapbook contains various church photos, both in color and black and white. This collection dates mainly from the late 1950s through the early 1980s.
Arrangement
Documents are arranged based upon original order.
Contents List
- Papers of Bonnie S. Ball (Box 1)
  - Tribute article to Bonnie Ball written by Gladys Stallard for the Appalachian Quarterly 1996.12 (Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from Jean Patterson of Tennessee requesting genealogical information on the Bramlett Family of Bedford County, Virginia. Includes Ball's research notes. 1972.1.22 (Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Ann Ryan of San Clemente, California requesting genealogical information on the Chapman Family. Includes Ball's research notes. undated (Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from Florence Cates of Kingman, Kansas regarding genealogical research of the Cates, Hess, Cunningham, Trumbo, Rinker and Cleveland Families. Includes Ball's research notes. 1962-1969 (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from Mary Neal Routzhon of Harlan, Kentucky requesting genealogical information on the Coulson Family. Includes Ball's research notes. 1960-1973 (Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from Sybil Barker regarding the Sage Family. Includes genealogical charts for the Sage, Barker and Cornett Families. 1972.11.15 (Folder 6)
  - Notes on the Cox Family undated (Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from E. Cutchenson of Atlanta, Georgia requesting information on the Delp-Rhudy Family 1984.3.19 (Folder 8)
  - General Index of Marriages for Scott County, Virginia 1800s-1930s (Folder 9)
  - Notes on Francisco Family research for wills. undated (Folder 10)
  - Notes on the Gaddy Family for Ruth Maxwell of Tennessee 1978 (Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous records compiled on the Glass Family undated (Folder 12)
  - Correspondence from Mrs. Paul Murff of Floydada, Texas requesting genealogical information on the Gwin (Gwyne) Family. Includes Ball's research notes. 1969.3.16 (Folder 13)
  - Notes on the Hale Family undated (Folder 15)
  - Correspondence from Mrs. Robert E. Spencer of Sonoma, California requesting genealogical information on the Harding Family. 1984.2.14 (Folder 16)
  - Notes on research of the Haven Family undated (Folder 17)
  - Correspondence with J.B. Havens of Stafford, Texas. Includes Ball's research notes. 1970s (Folder 18)
  - Notes on Jones Family research 1950s-1960s (Folder 19)
  - Notes on Lohr Family research undated (Folder 20)
  - Notes on Martin Family research undated (Folder 21)
  - Notes on Moore Family research undated (Folder 22)
  - Notes on Ott Family research undated (Folder 23)
  - Notes and correspondence on the Sayer (Sawyer) Family 1960s (Folder 24)
  - Notes on Stealy Family research undated (Folder 25)
  - Notes, correspondence and genealogical charts on the Todd Family. undated (Folder 26)
  - Notes on Grayson County, Virginia undated (Folder 27)
  - Notes on Wright Family research undated (Folder 28)
  - Notes on Tazewell County, Virginia undated (Folder 29)
  - Notes on Smyth and Washington Counties, Virginia undated (Folder 30)
  - Notes on Wise County, Virginia undated (Folder 31)
  - Records from Rowan County, North Carolina containing information on earliest settlers undated (Folder 32)
  - Grayson County Historical Society Newsletters 1983 (Folder 33)
  - 1850 Census of Mercer County, Virginia, 1810 Census of Giles County, Virginia and Index of non-military service in the American Revolution in Western Virginia. undated (Folder 34)
  - Three notebooks containing information on censuses, land records and marriage records for various Virginia counties undated (Folder 35)
  - Index of Border Settlers of Northwestern Virginia, 1765-1795 undated (Folder 36)
  - List of first settlers of Jamestown, Virginia. undated (Folder 37)
  - Scrapbook of various Virginia church histories with photographs. undated (Folder 38)